another tool we have in discovery tactics that was an angry AP scanner. So this is also
one of the tools that was commonly abused by the threat tactics to perform or discovery
scanning against the network infrastructure and the organization. So let me show you something.
You can get the angry AP scanner from Google. So you can search for a hangry IP scanner
download. So this is the one you can download the angry IP scanner from this website.
If you need to install in MacOS Linux or anything in even Windows you can get that. So once
the angry AP scanner get download. You can perform the scanning the same. I have installed
angry IP scanner in this machine. So I don't want to repeat the scanner because my
environment was standing with multiple security tools. It will detect it will trigger
an iZ alerts. So yeah, you need to view the input here for IP range and you can perform
the start scanning. So it will start a scan and it will watch for all the things whether
any port source online, anything happening on the environment or not. What are the
hostiles live and active and non active host. So let me show you how to perform the scanning
in the console the command line. So this is also one of a GUI based tool as well as we can
use the command prompt to scan the environment. So here you can find the PowerShell commands
here. So see program files angry AP scanner IP scan.exe. You need to install the angry
AP scanner in the environment in the device. And you need to give the mentioned a path.
And you need to do the is Q range dash F range as an F and output as this one and scan
wrestle.exe. The scan will be saved in the scan wrestle.csv. Currently my visual box
do not have a Microsoft Office. So I just draw and drop the results in my personal machine.
So here you can find these things. So let me try scanning and I will show you how this
will perform a scan. So now we can see it was scanning the environment and the host name
must be fine. So it will be a little bit faster than the advanced IP scanner what I
what I upset you now. But this is one of a really good tool to perform a scanning.
Okay. Let's wait for the scan to be get completed.
I will draw the delete this. Let's post this one and let's delete this one and now let's
move this file. Let's open this one. Ah yeah. Here you can find the IP ranges and the
ports 84.43 has been opened and you can filter out this one and you can get the other
end. Sorry. You can uncheck the n by a nothing applicable. So might be there was a half
line host. Okay. So you can see this all or the host that was online. Let's save this
in next door. Okay. So either one discovery tool will be enough. Either it will be an
angry IP scanner or advanced IP scanner. But it makes parents I have seen three of the tools
that was performed commonly for discovery tactics. One is advanced IP scanner, angry IP scanner
and net scan. So the next video we are going to see the net scan to perform the scanning.
Okay. So that's all. Let's hop off from here and we'll continue our discussion in the
next video. See you guys. Bye bye.